M. Esat OZEN

Full Stack Software Developer Greater Boston Area, MA (203) 278 6572 ozenesat@gmail.com https://ozenesat.github.io/ https://github.com/ozenesat https://linkedin.com/in/ozenesat

Skills

JavaScript React.js Node.js

Python

Next.js

Express Mongoose

MongoDB

Ruby on Rails

Postman

PostgreSQL

Git/GitHub

Phabricator

jQuery

AJAX

JSON Handlebars

HTML CSS

Bootstrap

Linux/Ubuntu

Education

General Assembly

Software Engineer

Immersive

Middle East Technical University (METU)

Bachelor of Science Mathematics

Abstract Algebra

Combinatorics

Complex Calculus

Cryptography

Discrete Mathematics

Introduction to C

Number Theory

Leadership

President of the Student Council @ METU

Work Status

Green Card Holder

Summary

With a quantitative academic background and startup experience, able to master new skills quickly. Enjoys breaking down and solving complex problems with analytical thinking in transferring innovative ideas into the codebase. Experienced in diverse work areas in three different countries as a highly adaptive world citizen.

Experience

Rapic.io - Remote

May 2020 – Present

Front-End Developer

- Designing, implementing and testing the application from scratch with Next.js.
- Integrating OAuth functionality into the React application with back-end server.
- Working with 6 developers globally over Phabricator with scrum methodology.

General Assembly - Boston, MA

February 2020 – May 2020

Software Engineer Immersive

- Completed 12 weeks/500+ hours of intensive Full Stack Development instruction.
- As a capstone project developed full-stack SPA, <u>Photo Collector</u>, using the technologies React, Node, Express, MongoDB, with OAuth and third party APIs.
- Completed 4 full-stack web applications in 4-day sprints independently & collaboratively and practiced Agile methodology.
- Learned and applied 15+ new languages, libraries, databases, and other technologies. Utilized Git and GitHub for version control.
- Greatly exceeded curriculum expectations by completing ~100 extra hours of additional material.
- Built quality RESTful APIs and integrated data from third-party APIs.

Ace It Education - Boston, MA

May 2019 – February 2020

Web Developer

- Created and maintained the two websites of the company with WordPress.
- Provided technical support for the weekly events and classes of the company.
- Managed social media and website content. Advertised the events via Eventbrite.

The Fix - Farmington, CT

May 2018 – May 2019

Stores Manager

- Managed the finances and personnel affairs of the company's branches at four different locations.
- Efficiently managed a yearly budget of ~\$1 million and increased the profitability of the company by 10% with user and market research.
- Worked on improving sales strategies and customer satisfaction. Established the use of alternative products and services tailored to customer needs.

Zaman Media Group - Ankara, Turkey

May 2014 – April 2016

Correspondent

- Worked with editors and senior correspondents as a team to cover all of the latest political news from the Capitol. Reported on judicial news from the courts.
- Acted as assistant to the Executive Officer in the Ankara office of the media outlet.